# **Jim Pollaro**

## **Software Engineer**

San Francisco, CA · 503.789.6078 · jim.pollaro@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jim-pollaro · Github: pollaro

## **Summary**

I am a web developer with an interest in web applications built with JavaScript or Python. A big believer in making code readable and reusable, I look to make my code and applications clean and efficient. I have a strong background in engineering and science from my background doing academic research in MRI. I love problem solving and trying new technologies.

### **Technical Skills**

Front-End Development: HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, Angular, React, Vue

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Ruby, typescript

**Database:** MySQL, SQLlite, Postgresql, MongoDB, MongoDB, GraphQL **Development Tools:** git, Bootstrap, npm, MVC, Mongoose, Postman **Frameworks:** Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails, Express.js, Node.js

### **Professional Experience**

Full Stack Engineer • Oct 2020 to Nov 2022

Synthego, Menlo Park, CA

- Member of LIMS team
- Implementing stock reservation system
- Refactor Cell information site for sales team
- Technology: Django, React.js, Redux, HTML

Software Engineer • Nov 2018 to Oct 2020

DrChrono, Sunnyvale, CA

- Implement a new payment processor into existing payment system. Allows users to pay by credit card, credit card number, and saved credit card. System is PCI compliant
- Redesigned and developed a billing profile system that is faster and more efficient. This was needed due to scaling issues
- Technology: Django, Python, Angular.js, MySQL, HTML, Javascript, GraphQL

Software Engineer (volunteer position) ● Sept 2018 to Nov 2018

Valley Medical Center Foundation, San Jose, CA

- Adding features to auction platform. Working on generating invoices for winners, allowing clerks to view all items won, and participating in code reviews
- Technology: JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, jQuery

Consultant • Jan 2016 to Dec 2016

Research Associate • Aug 2007 to June 2015

Oregon Health & Science University, Advanced Imaging Research Center, Portland, Oregon

- Wrote image processing scripts in Python
- Helped implement national multi-site studies
- Constructed devices and equipment for MRI acquisition
- Performed maintenance and ran acquisitions on MRI

#### Associate in Research • Aug 2004 to May 2007

Duke University, Center for In Vivo Microscopy, Durham, North Carolina

- Constructed animal monitoring and ventilation system using LabView
- Constructed devices and equipment for MRI acquisition
- Performed maintenance and ran acquisitions on MRI

#### **Education**

M.S. Biomedical Engineering B.S. Electrical Engineering Purdue University, Indiana